Toni Lozano Fernández

IOS Developer

Email aj.lozano.fernandez@gmail.com

+34 686 667 152 **Phone**

Github https://github.com/ajlozano

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/tonilozano

Personal Summary

I am a self-driven iOS Developer, life learner with professional background in electronic industry. After more than 10 years in electronic engineering I've acquired a solid base in problem solving and low level programming. In that stage I developed projects that required hardware design and firmware development to implement embedded systems, which allowed me to understand the importance of efficient code, attention to detail, good communication and great teamwork

In recent years the mobile sector has awakened my interest, specifically the iOS technology, which has given me to develop several projects and create my own apps. However, my adventure in the mobile sector began with the development of small projects in Android. I also feel great passion for gamedev, where I've been able to create basic projects with Unreal Engine and something more complex in Unity.

Work Experience

Freelance iOS developer 2021 - present

Develop own projects for iOS devices using Swift. Identify and troubleshoot technical issues in applications, as well as perform thorough testing and debugging to ensure solid, bug-free performance.

Since the mobile development field is rapidly evolving. I must keep up to date on the latest trends, technologies and best practices. In addition to researching and learning new tools, frameworks and APIs relevant to the iOS platform, all while keeping in mind to maintain clean and efficient code by using SOLID principles.

Hardware Designer Sept 2016 - Dec 2021

Neec Audio Barcelona

Responsible of hardware design oriented to Professional Audio devices whith innovative solutions

Firmware and hardware developer Aug 2014 - Aug 2016

Zolertia S.L.

Responsible of all Hardware design and firmware development for products like Z1, Re-mote, etc. Including schematics design and PCB multi-layer, component selection and verification based on circuit simulation, prototype testing.

R+D Technician June 2008 - Aug 2014

Advancare S.L.

Project development in all stages of production of custom-made devices, from planning to spec documentation, hardware design, firmware development, integration and testing.

Skills & Technologies

iOS dev:

Game dev:

3D - 2D

Others:

Xcode Unity Swift C# **UIKit** C++

RESTful APIs Visual Studio JSON parsing Real-time animations Core Data Real-time physics Firebase collisions

SwiftUI **MVC** MVVM

Git **VIPER** Github **Unit Testing**

Agile methodologies Cocoapods Realm SourceTree

Auto Layout Notion OOP Slack Clean Code Trello

Android dev:

Android SDK

Java Kotlin Xml MVC MVVM **RESTful APIs SQLite**

Extra information

Languages:

Spanish & Catalan (native), English

Full Driving License

Education

Universitat Oberta de Catalunya June 2022 - Oct 2022 Android development course.

iOS & Swift - iOS App Development Bootcamp 2021 Udemy - Angela Yu

Beginning C++ Programming 2022

Udemy - Dr. Frank Mitropoulos

UNIR - La universidad de internet Oct 2018 - Oct 2019 Game design and development master degree.

Interactive Programming in Python 2015 Coursera.

Institut Obert de Catalunya Sept 2014 - June 2015 CFGS Multiplatform Application development.

Institut Escola del Treball Sept 2006 - June 2008 CFGS Electronic products development.

Projects

Somnum Tracker - iOS

SomnumTracker is a usefull app for reporting and managing daily sleep duration stats. Developed using VIPER architecture pattern and mix view implementation with some parts of SwiftUI.

https://github.com/ajlozano/SomnumTracker https://apps.apple.com/us/app/somnum-tracker/id6450696537

Wish I Watch - iOS

Wish I watch is an easy way to search, store and read about specific movies and series. You can search for a title, get specific information using WebView and store it in yout wishlist using Core Data.

https://github.com/ajlozano/Wish-I-Watch

Bad Weed Never Dies - Unity

Survival 2D game developed for a GameJam in itch.io.

https://github.com/ajlozano/Wish-I-Watch https://anthonayer87.itch.io/bad-weed-never-dies